Information System Project Proposal
 
Surname $ Initial	Student Number	Email
Mabasa MM	          211197331	Millicia68@gmail.com
Sello B                	212408484	Bkhosa97@gmail.com
		

BACKGROUND

Information System is an endeavor that customers can use. 
Information System is the website where customers register and request for the available components. 
 This project is to establish E-Commerce computer components shopping website.
 The website   must provide information and sell products to B2B and B2C. 

OBJECTIVES

1.   Computer Components Online shopping website must be created.
2.   The website must allow users to update their account information.       



PROBLEM STATEMENT

Customers can browse through the product catalog and add their items to shopping cart.
 They can proceed to checkout as long as their shopping cart is not empty.
 Customers will be required to login to the system when they proceed with the checkout, 
or they can create an account if they are not yet registered.
 The order will be charged to the credit card registered in customer's account.
 Customers need to provide full names, email address, phone number,
 credit card and billing address details when creating an account.
 Customer can login to the system to maintain his or account information,
 such as changing phone number, address, and credit card details,
 and check the status of his orders.

Upon order received, the sales staff will process the order by charging the customer's credit card.
 Once the order has been charged, they will then mark the order as paid and pass it to Courier
 Company and deliver them to the customer. If the items that the customer ordered are out of stock, 
then the order will be marked as on hold. Once the item(s) arrived, 
the order will be passed to the courier company for delivery.
 Courier Company will pack the item(s) with standard packaging, but if the order is marked as gift,
 then the item(s) will be packed as a gift.

If the items arrived with damage, customer can contact us using the contact page.
 Courier Company will collect the item from customer and sales staff will refund the money for that item.


PRELIMINARY REQUIREMENTS

1.	A system that allows administrator to access and update client equipment hardware from any location. 
2.	A self-help system that allows clients to directly enter their requests, 
   allow administrator to document the work done on those requests, and for clients, 
   administrator and management to be able to see the history and status of each request. 
•	The system must be operational seven (7) days a week, 365 days a year. 
•	The systems’ response time must not exceed 5 seconds. 
•	The system must support 30 users online simultaneously. 
3.	A system that generates statistics and reports so that management can pursue continuous improvement 
  in offering the best service to their clients. 
•	The system must produce these reports and statistics every time management makes a request. 
•	Otherwise reports and statistics must be produced automatically on the last Friday of every month. 


SOLUTIONS TO RESOLVE THE PROBLEMS DISCLOSED

	Make sure that only technicians can enter work records and new equipment. And only   technicians should mark a service as resolved. 
•	The system must provide logon security at the operating system level and when they have to access the intranet as well as the application. 
•	All transactions must have an audit trail. 
•	Management must approve new customers requesting new equipment. 
•	The system must create an error log file that includes the error type, description and time
•	Allow clients to submit service requests and problems 
•	Track the progress of the request until it is resolved. 

		

